For anyone who's ever won. For anyone who's ever lost. And
for everyone who's still in there trying.
Working Girl is a comedy, romance, drama film directed by Mike Nichols.
When a secretary's idea is stolen by her boss, she seizes an opportunity
to steal it back by pretending she has her boss' job.
Tess McGill, played by Melanie Griffith.
Jack Trainer, played by Harrison Ford.
Katharine Parker, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Mick Dugan, played by Alec Baldwin.
Cyn, played by Joan Cusack.
Oren Trask, played by Philip Bosco.
Working Girl is a 1988 American romantic comedy drama film directed by Mike Nichols, written by
Kevin Wade, and starring Harrison Ford, Sigourney Weaver, and Melanie Griffith.
Its plot follows an ambitious secretary from Staten
Island working in mergers and acquisitions.
The secretary, who has been going to business night school, pitches a
profitable idea, only to have her new boss attempt to take credit.
When her boss is laid up with a broken leg, she secretly takes over her
boss's role to prove her capabilities in the corporate world.
The film's opening sequence follows Manhattan-bound commuters on the Staten Island Ferry accompanied by Carly Simon's song "Let the River Run", for which she received the Academy Award for Best Original Song and the Golden Globe Award for Best Original
Song, and the Grammy Award for Best Song Written Specifically for a Motion Picture or Television, making her the first artist to win this trio of awards for a song composed and written, as well as performed, entirely by a single artist.
The film was met with critical acclaim, and was a major box office
success, grossing a worldwide total of $103 million.
Working Girl was nominated for six Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Actress
for Griffith, while both Weaver and Joan Cusack were nominated for Best Supporting Actress.
The film won four Golden Globes (from six nominations), including Best Motion Picture – Musical or
Comedy, Best Actress – Musical or Comedy for Griffith, and Best Supporting Actress for Weaver.
It also received three BAFTA nominations: Best Actress for Griffith, Best
Supporting Actress for Weaver, and Best Original Score for Simon.
The film explores themes of new york city, strong
woman, love triangle, clerk, empowerment.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.